Guide to the Charles Hill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Hill Papers
1764-2018
1975-2018
MS 2070
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
35.92
(88 boxes)
The collection consists of the personal papers of Charles Hill. Materials include Hill's correspondence, writings, lectures, course materials, research files, notebooks, and diaries. The bulk of the collection consists of course materials and subject files. Key aspects of the collection include correspondence with former Secretaries of State Henry Kissinger and George Shultz and copies of Hill's notebooks he kept as a member of the State Department, including his time spent as an executive aid to Shultz from 1985-1989. In addition, the papers document Hill's wide range of academic interests, particularly in the classics, and the diverse array of courses he taught at Yale in the Directed Studies program and the Brady-Johnson Program in Grand Strategy since the 2000s. The collection also contains drafts of chapters from Hill's book, Grand Strategies: Literature, Statecraft, and World Order. Materials range from 1764-2017.
Hill, Charles, 1936-
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in seven series and one addition: I. Correspondence, 1980-2017, II. Course Materials, 1995-2017, III. Research Materials and Subject Files, 1764-2017 IV. Lectures and Talks, 1999-2016 V. Writings, 1975-2017 VI. Notebooks, 1979-1989, VII. Restricted Files, 1981-2017.
Conditions Governing Access
Series I through Series VI are open for research.
Series VII consists of restricted files. Correspondence and subject files related to Henry Kissinger and George Shultz are closed to researchers until five years after the date of Kissinger's and Shultz's deaths, respectively. The administrative files (containing information on the Brady-Johnson program in Grand Strategy, academic appointments, and other departmental issues) are restricted until 1 January 2051 by Yale University policy. Contact Public Services for information on requesting access to restricted university records. Hill's personal notebooks and desk diaries contain student names and grades and are restricted until 2093 as established by Yale Corporation regulations http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles Hill, 2017 and 2018.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Hill was born on April 28, 1936. Hill attended Brown University and graduated with a Bachelor of Arts in 1957. He then received a juris doctorate and Master of Arts degree in American studies from the University of Pennsylvania in 1960 and 1961. Hill's lengthy tenure in the State Department began in 1963 working as a vice council in Zurich, Switzerland; he was then assigned to Taichung, Taiwan as a Chinese language officer, and made a political officer in Hong Kong in 1966. In 1970, Hill was appointed a fellow at the East Asia Research Center at Harvard University. Hill then turned down a diplomatic assignment in South Vietnam in the Civil Operations and Rural Development Support (CORDS) but was reassigned to an embassy post in South Vietnam in 1971. He returned to the United States in July 1973, and began a short stint working for the assistant secretary of Cultural Affairs, writing policy documents and briefs on U.S-China relations. This position lasted a few months, whereupon Hill became a close aide to Ambassador Ellsworth Bunker and played a central role in negotiations over the Panama Canal treaties. In 1974, Hill became part of the policy planning staff within the State Department, as well as a speechwriter and advisor for then Secretary of State Henry Kissinger. This began a longstanding professional relationship and personal friendship between Hill and Kissinger. During the Jimmy Carter administration, Hill worked in the U.S. Embassy in Tel Aviv. A series of appointments in the Middle East followed: one as director of Arab-Israeli affairs, and the other as Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Middle East. Hill was then appointed executive aide to George Shultz in 1985, a position he served until 1989. After teaching at Cornell University as a Clark Fellow, Hill went on to advise the Secretary General of the United Nations, Boutros Boutros-Gali, from 1992 to 1996.
After leaving the U.N. (and public service) in 1996, Hill turned to a career in university teaching. Hill taught at Stanford University from 1995 to 1998, and has taught at Yale University since 1998. He authored two books in this time: Grand Strategies: Literature, Statecraft, and World Order (2010), and Trial of a Thousand Years: World Order and Islamism (2011). Along with Paul Kennedy and John Lewis Gaddis, Hill was a founding member of the Brady-Johnson Program in Grand Strategy at Yale University, where he was appointed a senior lecturer and diplomat-in-residence.
Cold War; Diplomacy; Grand strategy and statecraft; Art and literature; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Shultz, George Pratt, 1920-; Hill, Charles, 1936-; Yale University--Faculty
- Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of correspondence to and from Charles Hill. Correspondence primarily consists of emails printed by Hill, and is with individuals affiliated with Yale. Notable correspondents include Fouad Ajami, Elizabeth Bradley, David Brooks, William F. Buckley, Jr., John Lewis Gaddis, Paul Kennedy, James Mattis, and Norma Thompson. Much of the correspondence to Hill solicits his thoughts on domestic and world affairs, grand strategy, literature, and the discipline of history. Student correspondence is also in Series I; and this correspondence conveys Yale students' appreciation for Hill--for the academic rigor of his courses and the intellectual influence he had upon them.
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged alphabetically.
  - General
    - A-C, 2006–2017 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - D-I, 2006–2017 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - J-Q, 1986–2017 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - R-Z, 2002–2017 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alphabetical
    - Ajami, Fouad, 2012–2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bradley, Elizabeth, 2015–2016 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brady, Nicholas, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Brooks, David, 2013–2014 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Buckley, Jr. William F., 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Edel, Charles, 2013–2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gaddis, John Lewis, 2002–2017 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gaddis, John Lewis--on dinner with Hillary Clinton, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Grand Strategies, 2008–2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Eliana, 2006–2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Kennedy, Paul, 2006–2017 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Khan, Sulmaan, 2006–2016 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Kushner, Jared, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - LaFeber, Walter, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Levin, Richard, 2006–2012 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mattis, James, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Meade, Larry, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Miscamble, William (Bill), 2006–2014 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nelson, Nick, 2012–2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Niemeyer, Julie A., 2011 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - O'Connell, Aaron, 2014–2015 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Polak, Benjamin, 2013–2017 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Rahmatullah Hasemi case, 2006–2014 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Random House, 2005–2009 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Renaming Calhoun College, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Solman, Paul, 2015–2017 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Student correspondence, 1995–2009 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Thompson, Norma, 2006–2015 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, Robert, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Worthen, Molly, 2006–2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Course Materials
  Series II contains course materials related to Hill's courses taught at Yale and Stanford. Materials include syllabi, lecture notes, and subject files used to prepare for lectures, assignments, and class sessions. Some files also contain correspondence and memorandums. Series II also includes materials for Hill's grand strategy courses, including notecards for crisis simulations conducted by students in the Brady-Johnson Program in Grand Strategy.
  Series II is arranged alphabetically.
  - General
    - American Empire: Literature, Architecture, Diplomacy (HUMS 333b), 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The American Epic (of experience), 2009–2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - American Epics war/thought, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - American Literature and Statecraft, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bibliography (Stanford course), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Charles Hill courses, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Charles Hill courses Grand Strategy/International Studies/Directed Studies/Humanities, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Charles Hill courses (Humanities), 2002–2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Churchill course, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Consciousness--Comprehensive fall term, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Course notes--various, 2005–2016 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Dante--Stanford course notes, 1968–1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Democratic Epic (course), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Democratic Epic (syllabus), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Directed Studies: History and Politics--course reader, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Directed Studies--CH memos, 2000–2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Directed Studies--Darwin, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Directed Studies--Darwin, Marx, Fraser, Freud, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Directed Studies--Full set syllabus, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Directed Studies--"The Study of Texts," Allan Bloom, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Directed Studies--syllabus, notes, and exchanges, 2000–2001 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Midterm for "Aristotelian Statecraft", 2013 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous (St. Dominic's dog), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - New courses, 2011–2014 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Other Times, Other Rivers", 2002–2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Religion and Statecraft, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "The Statecraft of Zionism", 1988–2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Stanford courses on international relations, 1990–1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Stanford GSB Course Reader (originals), 2008 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - Strategic Adventures--course notes, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Various course syllabi, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Yale for Life, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Yale--National University of Singapore (grand strategy), 2013 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Yale--Singapore (syllabus), 2013 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Architecture of Power
    - Adams--Mont St. Michel and Chartres, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Age of Tourism, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Airships/Dirigibles Moffet N.A.S., 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Alhambra, 2004–2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - American Architectural Fantasies: Cole, Field, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - American Monument, 2001–2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Amero-Liberian Architeture, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "An American Cathedral," "Rouen Cathedral," The Georgia Review, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Amiriya in Rada, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Architecture and American Military Power, 2004–2005 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Architecture and Society, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Architecture Articles, 2003–2007 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Architecture (Halle) Parthenon/Charties, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Architecture Notre Dame, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Architecture Now (if you can do it, you must do it), 2006–2007 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Architecture of Diplomacy, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Automobiles (American Grilles) (houses of power and speed), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Aztecs (entire city a temple), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Baroque Cardinal Borghese (Bernini), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Battleship New Jersey, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Beijing Summer Palace (demonstration town), undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Bernini St. Peter's Square, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Bethlehem Steel (and grain elevators), 2004–2005 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Bibliography, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Bin Laden, 9/11 and World Trade Center-Pentagon toy, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Boorstin--The White House/ The Capitol, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Borobudur, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Brombert "Living Stones of Notre Dame", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Buildings in The Tale of Genji, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Byzantium, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Camp David and Annapolis, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Car Shapes (The "scope" of things to come), 2008 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - The Case of Rome, 2003–2007 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Catholic Cathedral of Los Angeles, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - CH: Chancellery, Symbol, Fort (review of Architecture of Diplomacy), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Chinese architecture, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Chrysler Building, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Cole, Thomas--The Architect's Dream, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Contemporary (back-up), 2007–2008 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Corregidor (mile-long barracks), undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Corregidor (National Geographic), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Course Readings [1 of 5], 2005–2006 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Course Readings [2-5], 2005–2006 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Decisions and Identity, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Diplomatic settings, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dome of the Rock, 1883–2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Embassy architecture, 2009–2010 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The Escorial, 1963–2010 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Feng Shui, 1993–2005 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Final Exams, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - The Flatiron Building, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Fonthill Abbey, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "For the New Railway Station in Rome," Richard Wilbur, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, Ennis-Brown House, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Gare Saint-Lazare, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - The Gas Station in America, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Gaudi and the World Trade Center, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Gaudi--Hellenic Temple of Mediterranean Gothic, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Gibbon: quote on Ruins, 2004–2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Germany: 1900, 1764 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Giedion: Beginnings of Architecture, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Giedion: "Streamlining and Full Mechanization", 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Goldhill Jerusalem: Temple, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Grand Central Terminal (Houses of Power and Speed), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Great Wall of China, 1988–2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Greenwich, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Grotto, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Ground Zero Design (Libeskind), 2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Haghia Sofia (notes), undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Haghia Sofia--Byzantium, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Hassan II mosque, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Hecht "Houses as Metaphors: The Poetry of Architecture", 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Heidegger, Buildings, Dwellings…, 1993–2003 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Heidegger's Hutte, 1993–2003 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Henry VIII and Tudor Palaces Architecture, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Henry James and the Shadow of the Roman Empire, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - High Gothic Cathedral, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Hilton Hotels and the Cold War, 1995–2003 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Hitler: Plans for Berlin, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Hit List: (what this course is not), 2007 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - HMS Dreadnought, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - HMS Inflexible (from Fisher's Face), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Hoag, Islamic Architecture, 2002–2005 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Hodges, William, 1744-1797 (course start), 2005 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Hollander, John, "Upon Apthorp House", 1978 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Hoover Dam and HMS Dreadnought, 1906–2005 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Housing the Airship, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - International Studies--architecture, 1998–2001 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - International Studies--Architecture Philadelphia Grid Ship of State, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Israel's Security Barrier, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Israel's Security Barrier--International Court of Justice "Advisory Opinion", 2004 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Israel: the Supreme Court, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Italian Renaissance in Italy, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - James J. Hill home, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - John Soane and the Bank of England, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Kanan and Mohamed Makiya, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Karl Friedrich Schinkel (Gordon Craig), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Kingdom, Empire, and State, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Lakehurst Naval Air Station, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Lenin's tomb, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Literary Architecture: the structure of Proust's In Search of Lost Time, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Lubavitch--770 Eastern Parkway, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Macauley, Rose--Pleasure of Ruins, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Manifest power, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mao's tomb, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Maya: Tikal, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Maya (war and torture), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Metropolitan Opera, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Midterm, 2006–2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Military industrial might, 1879–2006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Milton, "Pandemonium" and the Bower (From Temple to Castle), 1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Ministries of Defense, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Mississippi steamboats, 1942–1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Monasteries (and Virgil, T.S. Eliot), 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Monasteries, Western Europe, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Monuments, Vietnam Veterans Memorial, etc., 1990–1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Mumford, The Brown Decades, "Towards Modern Architecture", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Mumford, Sticks and Stones (the imperial façade), 1955 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Mussolini's Rome, 2005–2007 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Nelson and Olin Monumentality of Time (giant clocks), 2003 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Nelson Wu Beijing Illustrations, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - New England cabin/hut, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - New England meeting houses, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - New York skyline, 2001–2002 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Nietzche on architecture, 1878 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Notes, 2004–2005 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Notes and published materials, 2004-2008 (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
    - Opera (A Song of Love and Death), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Opera Houses, 1991–2007 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Origins of Architecture, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Our Monuments, Ourselves, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Palladio and Statecraft, 2002–2004 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Pan Am Building (Juan Trippe), 2004 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Parthenon Frieze, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Penhurst, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Hill, Philadelphia city hall, 1961–2006 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Architecture, photographs from Henry James's New York edition, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Poe, Philosophy of furniture, 2010–2011 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Pope's grotto, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Polibius, the Roman military system, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Power is power perceived, 2000 September 15 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Prairie school, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Prison (eastern state), circa 2006 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Public monuments/sculpture book, 1985–2000 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Pyramid manifest, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Pyramid (Melville poem), 2006 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Railway station, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Reichstag, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Rockefeller center, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Rolls-Royce radiator, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Roman forum (ruins), 1973–2001 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Romania: Casa Poporului (Ceausescu), 2005 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Rome, Japan, and Medieval Europe, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Ruins, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Ruins: Longfellow-Colosseum Byron, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Ruins (notes), undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Ruins of Greece, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Ruins of Rome: T. S. Eliot and the presence of the past, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Rural architecture: Downing/Thoreau, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Saint-Exupery: the Wisdom of the Sands, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Savoia-Marchetti S.79, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Secretary of State's rooms (and neo-classic in United States), undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Service academics, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Shanghai architecture, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Shanghai bund, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Simon Goldhill, Herod's Temple, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Six buildings and the history of the world (Gaudi), 2003 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Spiritual power, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - The Stanford arch, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Statues/monuments, 1985–2003 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Structures of power, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Sydney opera house, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Syllabus, 2005–2006 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Syllabi, bibliography, and clippings, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Tabernacle/Tent (temple prototype), 2003 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Tel Aviv (Bauhaus), 2008 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Temple (and Herod's Palace and Masada), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Thoreau's Cabin, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Three Halls of State in Italy, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Tiananmen Opera House, 2006–2007 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Tolstoy, Anna Karenina (train), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Topkapi, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Tsar's pew 1551, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Turner, 1985–2003 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - TWA Terminal, JFK (Eero Saarinen), undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - TWA Terminal (JFK), Tourist Poets (Hullberg), "Versailles" (Merrill), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - 2001 (film), undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - United Nations headquarters, 2003–2004 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - United States Air Force Academy, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - United States Air Force Academy chapel, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - U.S. Capitol--J.Q. Adams and the design of the Pediment, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - USS New Jersey, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - USS Olympia (Adm. Dewey flagship), undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Vanbrugh and Mughal Mausolea, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Versailles--The Hall of Mirrors, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Victoria Terminus, Bombay, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Vienna Ringstrasse, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - The Wall as primary architectural event, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Western Style architecture in Shanghai, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - The Western Wall, Jerusalem, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - World Trade Center, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Wu, "The Chinese City of Man", 1963 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Ziggurat, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Association of Yale Alumni (AYA) courses
    - Alcibiades, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Actium--Horace and Shakespeare, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Book of Revelation: Christianity/Paul/ New Testament, 1997–2001 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Byron, 1958–2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Crusader Analogy and Israel (and on the state), 1949–2002 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Delian League, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Goeben (and Dardanelles), 1999–2002 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Herodotus and why the West wins wars, 2000–2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Lepanto and Cervantes (and the Ionian Mission), 1571–2001 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Mussolini, Henry Miler, Laurence Durrell, Thermoplyae II, 1978–1997 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Mycenae--Marriage--Furies, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Pan, 1969–2002 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Pan (from Homer, Herodotus, Thucydides), 2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Revelation/Joachim and "Empire" (Negri), undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Sicily 1943 (Patton), 2002 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Thuycidides, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 16)